

# Willy Fontenelle

# Senior Product Designer | Design system | Front-end React

Homepage: willyfontenelle.github.io Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/willyfontenelle

Portfolio: be.net/willyfontenelle

Medium: medium.com/@willyfontenelle

Nascimento: 15/05/1988 | Rio de Janeiro, RJ - Brasil

(21) 97155-9194 | willyfontenelle@gmail.com

## **Summary**

I've been working with digital design for over 10 years in app, platform and website projects as a UI/UX designer and proposing solutions that not only achieve business goals, but also improve user life and make development more efficient.

My work has always been very close to the technology area, developing interfaces and systems, but never leaving aside a full understanding of the problem, which is why I was also able to get involved with research and discovery processes.

I'm currently studying front end web programming and ReactJS, in order to extend my contribution to the team and the project and ensure more autonomy in the technical documentation of a design system.

Languages: Portuguese (native), English (advanced) and Spanish (intermediate).

# **Experience**

#### **Hurb** | 2022-2023 (Senior Design System Analyst)

- · Documentation of guidelines and best practices;
- Maintenance of design tokens, assets and components Web, IOS and Android;
- · Driving the DS evolutions roadmap;
- · Support to design and technology teams;

## **Ubook (Audimo)** | 2021 - 2022 (Senior Product Designer)

- Creation and documentation of the design library (styles, components and templates);
- UI prototypes and technical specification;
- · Homologation for the different iOS, Android and Web projects;

## Onawa | 2019-2021 (Product Designer)

- Conception and creation of the People Commerce platform, serving the Wine Events club;
- Creation and documentation of the design library (styles, components and templates);
- · Driving discovery and research methodologies;

### **Education**

- Workshop Design System Advanced Glauber Laender (Nubank) | 2023
- Design System Specialist Meiuca | 2023
- UX Team Summit (Design System) Mergo User Experience | 2022
- Design System in Code Meiuca | 2022
- Front-end Alura | 2021
- UX Foundations: Style Guides and Design Systems Linkedin | 2021
- Product Design bachelor's degree PUC-Rio | 2007-2011